ZEYUAN ZHAO

+86 153-8833-1889 ♦ Shanghai, China

E-mail \diamond Linkedin \diamond Homepage

RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am a second-year graduate student in School of Data Science and Engineering (DaSE) at East China Normal University. Before that, I received my double Bachelor degree in Computer Science and Technology and Financial Engineering from Sichuan University in 2022. My research interests mainly include heterogeneous graph representation learning, information networks analysis, graph prompt learning. I am also excited about trying new interesting and exciting directions in the future, e.g., large language models, AI agents.

EDUCATION

East China Normal University

Sep 2022 - Present

School of Data Science and Engineering/M.Eng in Software Engineering

Shanghai, China

Supervised by: Prof. Xiang Li

GPA: 3.70/4.00

Main courses: Theoretical Foundation of Data Science and Engineering, Machine Learning, Computer Vision, Large-scale Data Processing System

Sichuan University

Sep 2018 - June 2022

Experimental Class in School of Computer Science/B.Sc in Computer Science and Engineering Chengdu, China

GPA: 3.65/4.00 IELTS Score: 6.5

Main courses: Calculus, Linear Algebra, Statistics, Discrete Mathematics, Data Structure, Computer Network,

Database System, Operating System, Principle of Compiler, Financial Stochastic Processes

EXPERIENCE

Research and Development Intern

Dec 2023 - Present

Data Operation Department, Guotai Junan Securities Co.Ltd.

Shanghai, China

- Investigated high-value data asset identification based on Large Language Models (LLM).
- Participated in mining and identifying sensitive data based on LLM.

Research Intern

Jun 2023 - Oct 2023

Search Strategy Department, Baidu Inc.

 $Beijing,\ China$

-Mentor: Anfeng Cheng, Yiding Liu

- Proposed an idea of enhancing node representations for both link prediction task and node classification task in heterogeneous information networks.
- One conference paper is in submission (first author).
- Investigated graph prompt tuning framework from both feature and structure aspect.
- One conference paper is in submission (second author).

Summer Workshop

May 2021 - July 2021

School of Computing, National University of Singapore

Singapore

-Topic: AI/ML for Financial Services

- -Mentor: Anand Bhojan
 - Investigated some simple methods for analyzing stock market, e.g. LSTM, LR.
 - Developed a consulting website that provides services to users.
 - Got excellent(grade a-) in final evaluation and presentation.

Research Assistant

Nov 2020 - Mar 2021

School of Computer Science and School of Business, Sichuan University

-Mentor: Zhonghua Yu

Chengdu, China

- Developed a regression model to measure the readability of a financial statement, i.e., Chinese FOG Index.
- Optimized the model's performance with regularization methods.
- Participated in processing raw data and feature engineering.

PUBLICATIONS

• HetCAN: A Heterogeneous Graph Cascade Attention Network with Dual-Level Awareness

Zeyuan Zhao, Qingqing Ge, Anfeng Cheng, Yiding Liu, Xiang Li*, Shuaiqiang Wang

• PSP: Pre-Training and Structure Prompt Tuning for Graph Neural Networks

Under review
Qingqing Ge, Zeyuan Zhao, Yiding Liu, Anfeng Cheng, Xiang Li*, Shuaiqiang Wang, Dawei Yin

• Probabilistic Graphical Model for Robust Graph Neural Networks against Noisy Labels Under review Qingqing Ge, Jianxiang Yu, Zeyuan Zhao, Xiang Li*

SKILLS

Programming Language Python(primary), C++
Development Platforms Linux, MacOS

AI Framework Pytorch(primary), Mxnet

SCHOLARSHIPS & AWARDS

• Outstanding Student, East China Normal University	Dec 2023
• Golden Medal(Team Award), China Collegiate Programming Challenge Contest	Mar 2021
• Outstanding Student, Summer Social Practice, Sichuan University	Nov 2020
• Individual First-class Scholarship, Sichuan University	Oct 2020
• Individual First-class Scholarship, Sichuan University	Oct 2019